Come here.
Come.
Deliverance In Jesus' Name
Come on.
Who is she to you?
That's my ex-wife of 30 years.
There is a divorce and you are the cause.
Yes.
You are the cause of divorcing.
Yes, I am.
That is why I have to talk to her; she's the issue.
If she says, "Yes" it's yes;
if she says "No", it's no.
You are the cause of all this.
I am the cause.
At a time, God was blessing you with money.
Yes.
So, you messed up the whole thing.
Yes, I messed up.
A time when things were very difficult, she was with you.
Yes.
Now, things are good, you go out looking for women.
That destroyed your marriage.
It destroyed me.
You did not keep your marriage and this is a woman who can take care of you.
Because you have tasted many women who are zero.
I wasted 30 years.
You have not seen anything unless God restores this marriage.
I can't say this in the presence of my sister - I need to you see you.
This is sickness.
Yes.
It is sickness.
Deliverance In Jesus' Name
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Velma Garland and the man standing next to me is my ex-husband Carl Garland.
We are from the USA.
Last Sunday was the first time I attended The SCOAN.
The Prophet came over to us and he began to prophecy to me.
He told my husband that there was trouble.
He said that there was a divorce.
He asked where was the letter.
He was talking about the letter of divorce.
He looked at my husband and said, "You caused it".
He said, "When you had nothing she was with you
but when God start blessing and the money start coming in you start going out looking for other women".
This leads me to my problem.
I have been married to Carl for 30 years.
What the man of God said was very very true and accurate.
Women were calling me and leaving messages on my phone.
One even had the nerve to tell me that she'd been seeing him for 7 years.
One left a message and she has some things to say too.
I asked him about this.
He promised that he would never do it again but then it happened again.
I believed him because at that point we'd been together like 25 years.
We went on but then it happened again.
Because of his numerous affairs and his dealing with other women
he made me sick and this led to our divorce.
This divorce happened last year.
In the process of this year I was looking on TV and I came across Youtube and I saw Emmanuel TV.
I was watching the testimonies there, which were very compelling.
I live in US and this is Africa - I have never been to Africa.
I said, "If he can help those people..."
I was watching deliverances and demons being manifested.
These people were talking about how God had reconciled them after the deliverance.
I felt like if I could get here that maybe God could do the same thing for me and my marriage.
When I got here - this was the first time I had ever been here -
he laid hands on us and especially with my husband - he got delivered.
It started last Sunday - I started to see a change in him.
True repentance - I mean true repentance
Velma Garland & Ex-husband
Prophecy Testimony
and humility.
The arrogance was not there.
The affection for me came back.
Velma Garland & Ex-husband
Prophecy Testimony
He acts like he cares for me again.
Yesterday, we went to the prayer mountain.
At that prayer mountain we began praying.
I began to speak, as we were praying, in my heavenly voice because he didn't have the Holy Ghost.
Next thing I know; he starts speaking in tongues - he got filled with the Holy Spirit.
You listen to that?
You know; I told you that satan cursed people to lose control.
The man, my brother, was losing control in the past.
He lost control.
But now he has come to his senses.
He realized that what he had been doing in the past was wrong.
Now you can see.
This is why you have to cultivate and have a habit of forgiveness.
Forgive your neighbour.
What they have done to you is not out of hatred but they lost control.
Tell your neighbour, "Forgive your neighbour."
[Forgive your neighbour.]
You can see now.
He lost control.
Now he has come to his senses and realized...
Look at the testimony the wife is giving about him.
She says she was shocked.
When you were under bondage and you are released, you will see the true colours of yourself.
This is why the Lord says, "Forgive and forget".
You have to learn to forgive.
OK?
Whatever anyone might have done to you; please forgive and forget.
Hallelujah.
After the prayer, after touching him - I know it is not easy when you are not delivered.
Forgiveness must come through deliverance.
You cannot just say, "I forgive" - because it is not natural.
What happened to you is not natural.
It is spiritual and you must be released.
When you are released you will see the need of forgiveness.
Man of God, here is the divorce letter that you spoke about.
OK, this is the divorce letter I told about, "Look, this is the divorce. Where is the letter?"
Can you see?
I want to know if the decision that I made to divorce him is wrong or right and what has God have to say
about this reconciliation.
Yes, I'm happy.
Now, you have realized yourself and himself has realized himself.
He lost control then.
That is why he committed that shameful acts.
Now, we have realized ourselves.
Love is natural.
It is from the heart.
When the love comes from the heart no one can stop it.
Now, the love that comes from the heart is what you have to exercise.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Not because he says sorry, cries or suffers.
Because of this, because of that - no.
The love that comes from the heart - exercise it.
That is the love that can build a marriage.
Marriage is not for a while - it is forever.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The reason for which many marriages don't last is that this love is not from the heart.
If the love is from the heart, no matter what happens - the love from the heart will see you through.
What happened cannot destroy the marriage, cannot separate the marriage.
God can.
OK?
Because the love from the heart is love from God.
If God says "Yes" no one can say "No".
When the love comes from the heart, it does not mean there will be no tribulation.
There will be tribulation.
There will be all kind of crisis.
I was telling people yesterday that God's plan for our life causes us to face trouble.
Tell your neighbour, "God's plan for our life caused us to face trouble".
Your trouble could be temptation, persecution, sickness, or of any other kind.
God's plan for our life causes us to face trouble.
And we are all running for the trouble.
That trouble is the one that strengthens our life.
Are you with me there?
What strengthens our life?
[Trouble.]
We run for the very thing that brings strength for our life.
Tell your neighbour, "We run for the very thing that strengthens our life".
We run for the trouble.
Naturally, no one wants trouble.
Naturally, when you see a trouble coming you have to run.
It is that trouble that strengthens our life; just as fire strengthens gold, trouble strengthens our life.
Think about what I said; you will agree with me.
Just as fire strengthens gold.
You know; fire removes impurities from gold.
If not fire you cannot discover pure gold.
Impurities cover gold.
But when gold passes through fire, it removes those impurities.
You will now see a shining gold.
In the same day problem strengthens your life.
God's plan for our life causes us to face trouble.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "God's plan for our life causes us to face problem".
What is the problem?
When problem comes and you overcome it - you are promoted.
It comes, you are promoted.
Without problem you remain on a spot.
We run for the very thing that brings strength to our life.
What is the very thing?
Problem.
Your problem could be persecution, hatred, sickness, - just name it.
Look at homes today: divorce, divorce, divorce...
What is the cause of divorce?
Problem.
When you see a wonderful, successful marriage today...
When you meet them; in all areas they succeeded: children, home...
They are at their senior age.
When you meet them and ask them to counsel you, you ask them how did they manage
to keep the marriage from the beginning and you refused to divorce and you are at your senior age.
They will tell you that they have seen a lot in their lives.
A friend wanted to separate the marriage, an enemy came to separate the marriage,
satan came to separate the marriage, a lot of lies, a lot of stories.
Temptation came - we refused to separate.
Today, this is a wonderful marriage.
We run for the very thing that brings strength to our life.
We run for problem.
When problem comes we try to avoid it.
Whatever you can do you want to do it.
When a trouble come in the marriage; "your wife is this" - you, instead of sitting down and know that
trouble cannot separate a marriage from God,
you start to worry yourself.
You are no longer interested in the marriage; you go to another one.
The same applies to work.
You have attempted a lot of businesses and jobs.
You were once an architect, contractor...
There is nothing you have not done.
If they look in your pocket they will see different business cards.
Why?
Once you attend the business and you run to loss - that is the end of this business.
You are looking for another business.
You don't want to hear about any loss.
And that loss strengthens our life, to succeed.
Successful businessmen today, chairmen of many companies; when you meet them they will tell you
a lot of loss they have gone through.
A lot of "prison", damage, they run into debts, but they stood by.
You move from one business to another.
You don't want to hear anything about loss.
You don't want to hear about shortage.
You don't want to hear this.
When you hear about shortage you run, you abandon the business, you run to another.
You look; my brother is forwarding, he made it - you run to that.
You abandoned the other one.
This is why our life is like this.
There is no such business where you would not face trouble.
You keep running for trouble.
Look, you need to go to Heaven, if you say that you don't want to see trouble.
I have answered your question now.
Yes, you have.
If you are looking for a smooth marriage you need to go to Heaven.
Velma Garland & Ex-husband
Prophecy Testimony
This is one of the things that strengthens marriage.
Dispute.
Trouble.
One of the things that strengthens the marriage.
When you get to US meet successful aged marriage couple.
Meet them, let them counsel you; they will tell you what they have gone through in life to maintain their marriage.
So you may say, "Thank You, Jesus".
This is God's marriage.
Let me hear from our brother.
My name is Carl Garland.
I am from the USA.
I just want to say that last Sunday we were sitting over there and the man of God came and touched me.
He prophesied to me that he knew that there was a divorce.
He said that I had a lot of money and I was messing with a lot of women.
He said he saw a disease.
Look, we are not even expecting you to talk.
This is our mum here.
Once we hear from our mum we are OK.
Can you just give a hug to my mum and say "Thank You, Jesus".
Give her a hug.
Velma Garland & Ex-husband
Reconciled Through Prophecy
Forgive me, forgive me, forgive me...
I love you.
I want to tell...
Look, my brother.
I want to tell you that this woman is your mum.
Try to be a father.
OK?
Thank you.
He has gone through a lot of pain but because of Jesus he put everything behind.
Velma Garland & Ex-husband
Reconciled Through Prophecy
Thank you, man of God.
Thank you.
Man of God, I want to thank you for reconciling me with my wife.
I also want to say that I love you and I am very sorry.
And I want to say to you - listen to me:
that the marriage has been settled does not mean that the crisis has stopped.
There will be trouble and trouble and trouble...
The more the trouble the more your strength.
Strength comes to marriage through what?
[Trouble.]
Through trouble.
No temptation can separate this marriage.
[Amen.]
Velma Garland & Ex-husband
Reconciled Through Prophecy
Instead; the temptation will strengthen it.
As disagreement comes, strength comes.
Disagreement - agreement.
That is just life.
OK.
Thank you very much.
I want to meet you for counseling.
OK?
Thank you.
Give me your hand
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brother, come.
What would you do with those troubles coming to you?
I would not allow it to make me lose control.
Yes, you would not allow trouble to overwhelm you.
Because when it overwhelms you, you lose control.
Yes.
When something overwhelms you, like wine - when you are taking alcohol.
Your eyes begin to shine.
I know, when you sit sober with people taking alcohol - they will talk well after first cup.
But the second cup - you see their eyes becoming bright.
You ask them, "Are you all right?"
When trouble overwhelm you it takes control.
If you don't allow it to overwhelm you...
How can the trouble overwhelm us?
When we begin to look at the trouble, giving respect to the trouble as it is a way of life.
When it comes the end has not come.
You look at this trouble.
Remember, when you were in your mother's womb, when you were an embryo;
if trouble could not destroy you then - is it now that trouble would destroy you?
The SCOAN Sunday Service